I Am Not Your Negro is a documentary film directed by Raoul Peck.
Working from the text of James Baldwin’s unfinished final novel, director Raoul Peck
creates a meditation on what it means to be Black in the United States.
Narrator (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Narrateur (voix-off), played by JoeyStarr.
Self, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Self, played by Billy Dee Williams.
Self, played by Rod Steiger.
I Am Not Your Negro is a 2016 documentary film and social critique film essay directed by
Raoul Peck, based on James Baldwin's unfinished manuscript Remember This House.
Narrated by actor Samuel L.
Jackson, the film explores the history of racism in the United States through Baldwin's recollections of civil rights movement leaders
such as Medgar Evers, Malcolm X and Martin Luther King Jr., as well as his personal observations of American history.
The documentary was nominated for Best Documentary Feature at the 89th
Academy Awards and won the BAFTA Award for Best Documentary.
The film explores themes of society, race politics,
interview, martin luther king, racism.